Calvin Nicholas Moldenhauer

Full Stack Software Engineer
Monterey, California 93940
831-521-5704 | Calvickauer@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with a background in automotive repair. Strengths include effective communication, work ethic, teamwork, and being able to adapt to unexpected variables. Expertise in diagnosing, optimizing solution design, and meeting required specifications using HTML, JavaScript, Python and CSS.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: HTML | CSS | Python | JavaScript Frameworks: NodeJS | Express | REACT | Bootstrap | Django

Databases: MongoDB | SQL

Spoken Languages: English, (Proficiency level - Fluent), (Communication - read, write, speak) Russian, (Proficiency level - Intermediate/Conversational), (Communication - read, write, speak)

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly | Remote

June 2022 - December 2022

Successfully completed 500+ hours of expert-led instruction in Front-end and Back-end development and hands-on learning of fundamentals for the industry's most in-demand technologies. Developed projects include:

- Kandy's Payback: Canvas HTML game built using Javascript, CSS, HTML to ensure a fun, smooth and friendly user experience.
- Pet Adoption web application: Built a local pet adoption app to facilitate ease of search by using Express, Ejs, Javascript, CSS, bootstrap, and HTML.
- Catch-A-Ride web application: Built a local rideshare application to reduce carbon footprints and allow people to connect and travel at an agreed upon price. This application used React, Mongoose, Javascript, and CSS
- Face2Face web application: Built a webcam chat service for people to connect and communicate. Built using Python, Mongodb, CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SP Motorsports

November 2016 - December 2020

Track Support Master Technician, Hayward, California

- Head technician in charge of vehicle homologation and manage alteration to best suit the current series, location and conditions
- Supported the maintenance and safety of races and practice events for race or practice events with the goal of being the most efficient team of the current event
- Monitored, taught, and guided new technicians to understand the workflow and guide them through obstacles i've already overcome
- Debugged and tested code implemented in our tunes

C&C Repair

November 2010 - December 2019

Master Technician, Monterey, California

- Coordinated the purchase of oil by determining the best suppliers and quantities purchased, resulting in a 50% increase in oil profit margins
- Conducted quality parts audit on materials thought to be faulty, resulting in a 25% decreased disposable materials that are fully functional after being serviced.
- Supervised and trained up to 20 technicians to ensure automotive best practices were being followed.

Competition Motorsports

January 2015 - December 2016

- Maintained 10+ race cars on a daily basis to ensure drivers utilized safe and regulated vehicles while maintaining peak performance.
- Held meetings with customers/drivers in between heats to review footage and communicate techniques that would increase performance and lap times throughout the series.
- Developed an effective routine for checking, repairing and preparing race cars, resulting in extra time in between heats for more detailed inspections and/or repairs.

Jerry Woods Enterprises

November 2010 - December 2016

Track Support Master Technician, Campbell, California

- Provided track support according to customers personality and driving style resulting in a strong social connection to our customer and trust in the knowledge provided.
- Implemented an order of operations for the homologation process of spec 911's, which cut the build time by 20%
- Calibrated vehicles according to weather conditions, which increased driver performance and confidence.
- Found external resources to provide last minute parts which allowed our team to complete tournaments and retain customer confidence in our team.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Remote Certificate, Software Engineering Immersive (SEI)

December 2022